## ANDY ORFALEA

(805) 570 - 4449 | <u>aorfalea@gmail.com</u> | Santa Barbara, CA

https://www.linkedin.com/in/andy-orfalea/

https://aothree.github.io/

Motivated and resourceful data scientist with more than 10 years of senior management, as well as business administration experience. Adaptable, quick learner and always eager for the next challenge. Well versed in utilizing numbers, analysis, and visualization to discover business solutions. At my core, I'm a people person, plus, a top performer, working under pressure through collaborative and communicative team dynamics.

## **SKILLS**

Machine Learning and Deep Learning Tableau

Python Business Strategy

GitHub Operations Management

Git Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

General Assembly Remote

Data Science Immersive Fellow

January 2022 - April 2022

- 12-week, 500+ hour training program focusing on the ability to analyze, make sense of, convey data-driven facts from massive data sets, and predict what happens next through predictive modeling and pattern recognition.
  - Capstone project: Style of Play in the NBA Analyzing the evolution of styles of play implemented by NBA teams from 2012 to 2022, through the lens of data. Tools: K-Means Clustering, Python, and Tableau.

Freebirds Goleta, CA

General Manager

August 2011 - January 2022

- Analysis of financial statements and adjusting business strategy accordingly. Any recommendations to the owner had to be justified by statistical analysis.
- Accounts Payable. Ensuring 30+ vendors were paid in a timely manner.
- Administered and processed payroll, requiring accuracy of record keeping and timeliness to ensure compliance with all applicable state and federal laws.
- Managing 60+ employees including development, discipline, and termination.
- Recruiting and hiring. Interviewing, onboarding, and training.
- Food quality. Responsible for upholding the restaurant's extremely high standards for freshness and flavor.
   Developed systems to numerically evaluate and record the quality of our ingredients.

Assistant Manager

June 2008 - August 2011

- Projecting hourly sales, for every hour of operation, based on detailed analysis of historical sales data & trends. Based on these projections, scheduling and adjusting labor.
- Scheduling for 60+ coworkers
- Creating and re-formatting forms to analyze data using Microsoft Excel and Google Sheets.
- Maintaining and troubleshooting issues for computers, points of sale and surveillance systems.

## **EDUCATION**

General Assembly

Remote

Data Science Certificate

January 2022 - April 2022

Boston College Bachelor of Arts, English Boston, Massachusetts September 2004 – May 2008